Your son shoplifted from my store.
That is,
if you show me your sincerity.
Manager.
Twenty-three years ago,
within this jurisdiction,
there was a robbery
of an armored cash transport vehicle
belonging to the Mitsuba branch
of the Yamato Trust Bank.
The culprit, Nobukazu Oshima,
stole 30 million yen in cash
and fled to a forest five kilometers away.
He had an encounter with Officer Kiyohara.
There,
he and Officer Kiyohara shot each other,
and both died.
It's believed that Oshima's accomplice
took the 30 million yen
and Officer Kiyohara's gun,
but the 30 million yen and the gun
were never found
and their whereabouts are still unknown.
We thought we had
hidden that gun away with the crime
that the four of us committed
when we were in elementary school.
But…
The gun that was lost 23 years ago
was used in the recent incident,
which is a very serious matter.
That gun brought forth our reunion.
There are 14 security cameras installed
throughout the store,
and all of the footage is recorded here.
Where is the recorded footage stored?
In the computer over here.
Please show me the footage
from January 16th.
January 16th.
Here it is.
Detective Tobina,
what is camera number 14 filming?
Inside the store from the back.
It's the snack aisle.
Just as I thought.
Friday's footage from camera number 14
is the only one that's missing.
I wonder if the footage
contained something
that was inconvenient for someone?
Ms. Makiko Iwamoto
is clearly lying.
May I see the footage from January 17th?
Yes, ma'am.
Footage from camera 14 is here.
Ms. Nara, why do you say
that Ms. Makiko Iwamoto is lying?
She said that on Friday,
the day before the incident,
she came to this supermarket
to give her son his wallet.
My son called me
to say he had lost his wallet,
so I went to give him some money.
Your son called you on his smartphone?
No, he doesn't have a smartphone.
How did her son,
who doesn't own a smartphone,
manage to contact her?
A payphone?
Where's the payphone?
There are no payphones in this supermarket
or anywhere nearby,
and besides, how can he make a call
at a payphone without his wallet or money?
You're right.
He might have used the landline here
at the supermarket.
I'll request the call records.
No need to request it.
The call records should be arriving soon.
Ms. Nara, we received the phone call
records from the supermarket.
Please hand them to Detective Tobina.
Yes.
Come in.
There's a record of a call from the office
at Smile Sakuma to Ms. Iwamoto's salon.
Here it is.
- Is that right?
- Yes.
That doesn’t necessarily mean
that her son was the caller.
Right.
Hello?
Makiko?
- Junichi?
- Yeah.
What's up?
Um…
Oh,
am I being called to the station again?
No.
Can we talk privately?
When?
Today, if possible?
Okay.
Come to my shop. I’m available all day.
I want to talk about the day
before the incident.
Sure. Friday?
Yeah.
You said you went to the supermarket
after getting a call from your son.
Yeah.
Do you know where your son called from?
From the supermarket, I guess.
Which phone did he use?
I don't know exactly where,
but probably a phone
in the store's office or something.
Not a payphone?
He couldn’t have used a payphone
since he didn’t have his wallet.
Right.
Wait, am I a suspect?
No.
It’s not like that.
But you’re here as a detective, right?
There’s no need for you to worry.
It's all good.
Oh really?
Sorry to take up your time.
Since you’re already here,
I’ll cut your hair.
- Now?
- Yeah.
But I’m on duty.
No one would even notice.
They will if I return
with a cleanly trimmed hairstyle.
I won't give you
a cleanly trimmed hairstyle.
I’ll give you a really unique,
and edgy hairstyle.
That’ll be even more obvious.
Junichi,
you’re my childhood friend,
so I’ll only charge you 100,000 yen.
That's too expensive.
100,000 is insane.
It's only natural to help each other out.
- We're childhood friends after all.
- You're serious?
I sometimes cut Naoto’s hair too.
- Is that right?
- Yeah.
He brings me cake every time he comes.
Mont Blanc?
What?
You remember that I like Mont Blanc?
Yeah…
It came to me just now.
Then do you remember that as well?
That?
When you tried to kiss me.
Have you kissed anyone before?
What?
By the way,
I haven’t cut Keisuke’s hair
since we divorced four years ago.
Oh, it's not like we broke up
because we hated each other or anything.
I see.
We moved to my current house
after we got married.
Keisuke was working
at an architectural firm in Yokohama,
but he started a new firm in Tokyo
with a senior colleague.
He got so busy that he wasn’t able
to come back here very often,
so he suggested that we move to Tokyo.
He said we could sell the current house,
buy an apartment in Tokyo,
and find a tenant for this shop.
But I had regular clients here,
and there was also the matter of Masaki.
Ever since elementary school,
he set his sights
on Hamadai Middle School in Yokohama,
and he’d been attending cram school too.
In the end,
neither of us would compromise,
and couldn't reach an agreement,
so we decided to divorce.
I see.
What about you, Junichi?
Are you married?
- No.
- You have a girlfriend?
Yeah.
You do, huh?
Hey, can the four of us
get together sometime?
- You're changing the subject.
- That’s not it.
I want the four of us to get together.
Sounds good. When?
Tomorrow.
That’s short notice.
Naoto's older brother's wake is tomorrow.
I'm planning to go,
but what about you, Makiko?
That’s tomorrow, huh?
Yeah.
Apparently it's a quiet event
for just family members.
I see.
Let’s all go.
Can you tell Keisuke too?
Okay.
Come get a haircut again any time.
- Then see you tomorrow.
- Okay, see you.
Bye.
You're back early.
What's the matter?
Hey there.
Welcome home.
I have to leave right away.
I just came to get a change of clothes.
What?
Tomorrow, I have a meeting
and a wake in Mitsuba,
so I'll be staying there starting tonight.
It’s for work, right?
You've been going to Mitsuba a lot lately
and of course, I know it's for work, but…
Are you worried about Makiko and me?
The only time Makiko and I meet up
is when it concerns our son Masaki.
Yeah.
Sorry for making you worry.
How are you feeling?
I'm okay.
This little one is kicking a lot.
It’s a healthy baby.
Junichi came to confirm my story.
You were able to handle it?
Yeah.
If the lie is going to be exposed
later on anyway,
should we tell Junichi
about the shoplifting?
We've already discussed this.
We have to avoid anything that would
hinder Masaki's school acceptance.
Besides, if we talk about the shoplifting,
we'll have to lie about the threats too.
Okay.
We won't tell Junichi about
the shoplifting or anything else.
I need to tell Naoto
to go along with our story too.
How’s Masaki?
I haven't been able to
get an explanation of why he shoplifted.
Actually,
I talked to Masaki about that already.
What?
He seemed to be in shock
because the person
who caught him shoplifting was murdered.
He told you why he shoplifted?
Yeah.
Apparently he got in a fight
with Hisashi Machida.
Why?
My best friend called me a nerd.
Hisashi called you that?
He called me a clueless nerd.
I see.
So I tried to prove to him
that I'm not a nerd.
He shoplifted for something like that?
Don't say things like that
and corner Masaki, okay?
This is a sensitive topic for guys.
- So it’s my fault?
- What?
Because I made him study hard,
to get him into Hamadai Middle School?
I’m not saying that.
You’re doing a really good job
with Masaki.
If anyone is to blame, it's me.
I hadn't been seeing Masaki
because of work.
Then
do you want to make today
your once-a-month visit?
Sorry about what I said today.
Sorry, I have to finish up some work.
Okay.
Here. Let's eat.
Thank you.
Why don't we
go somewhere together next time?
Like an amusement park.
- No thanks.
- Really?
Is it too embarrassing
to hang out with your mom now?
Of course.
That's how it is, huh?
I guess that's only natural.
So, the gun
is in the possession
of the person who killed Sakuma, right?
- If the culprit didn't get rid of it yet.
- You're right.
Wouldn't it be difficult
to keep something like that hidden?
After all, it's a gun.
Where would you even hide it?
Oh man, I have absolutely no idea.
If the person who took
Officer Kiyohara's gun 23 years ago
is the same person who committed
this recent crime,
it means the culprit was hiding it
all this time, right?
If it’s not the same culprit, how did
the gun come to that person's possession?
Ms. Nara.
I'm going to Hideyuki Sakuma's
wake tomorrow night.
I might be able to get some clues.
Maybe I’ll go too.
What?
Actually, never mind.
We’ll attract too much attention.
Will your former classmates
be attending the wake too?
I'm not sure.
Is that right?
Yes.
Oh,
if you bump into Ms. Makiko Iwamoto,
try to get more information from her.
About the lie she told.
A mother went to the supermarket
to pick up her son.
The security footage from that day
of the snack aisle is missing.
Aside from returning a forgotten wallet,
you can probably think of another reason
why a mother would go
to the supermarket, right?
I'm sure I don't need
to spell it out for you. I'll be off now.
Oh.
Detective Tobina.
This part of your hair is nicely trimmed.
About the lie she told…
Aside from returning a forgotten wallet,
you can probably
think of another reason, right?
You were here?
Welcome back.
Thanks.
What's the matter?
You tried to kiss me.
What are you cooking?
I haven't decided yet.
Maybe I'll make soup.
Okay.
Is work tough?
No,
I just had it too easy until now.
- Oh really?
- Yeah.
You know the recent murder case?
The victim…
is the older brother of one of
my elementary school classmates.
Wow.
So you reunited with your classmate
as a detective
and a victim's family member?
Yeah.
- For the first time in 23 years.
- Wow.
What a strange coincidence.
Maybe the classmate is the suspicious one.
- Maybe I'll have beer after all.
- Yeah.
I know.
I won't tell Junichi
about Masaki's shoplifting incident.
I'm sure they won't ask you about it,
but if they do, you'll have to lie,
and I'm sorry about that.
I should be the one
apologizing to you instead.
What?
My brother blackmailed you…
But I was on a business trip abroad,
and I had left my smartphone in Japan,
so I couldn't do anything to help you
at a time like that.
Stop that.
You always have my back.
I'm sure you didn't want to come
to my brother's wake.
Nobody is saying it out loud,
but everyone in the family
is more relieved than sad that he's gone.
My mother is not related to my brother
by blood so it's understandable,
but even my father is relieved.
- Keisuke.
- Hey.
Keisuke is here.
Junichi too.
Express your emotions
Give the reward
To myself
Face myself, make no mistake
That's how I overcame it all
Yes! I'm really cool! I'm so cool!
I'm on a roll! I'm always…
You're still here?
Oh,
where's Mr. Tobina?
I'm sure he's at a reunion.
What?
I wonder where the gun went.
Yes.
I've been thinking about that too!
If the late Officer Kiyohara knew
that his gun would be used years later
to commit murder,
he wouldn't be able to die in peace.
The civilian who was killed
by a stray bullet at the bank
is the one who can't rest in peace,
don't you think?
Are you okay?
Yes…
You're right.
Thank you for coming today. Please drink.
Thank you.
Who would've thought
the four of us would meet again?
Let's make a toast.
A toast doesn't feel right.
It's a wake after all.
Don't worry about that.
He was a good-for-nothing brother.
Will I become a suspect if I say that
in front of the detective?
I knew he was a lousy older brother
ever since we were kids.
Maki, you'll drink beer, right?
Thanks.
I can't, I'm driving.
Okay.
I'm okay too.
All right.
Let's make a toast
without saying "cheers."
Then,
let's toast to our reunion.
The three of us met from time to time,
but we haven't seen Junichi
ever since we graduated.
Although I saw him once in passing.
- What?
- You saw me?
I haven't heard about this.
Where? When?
He's like a detective interrogating me.
He is a detective.
When I saw him,
he was still a police officer.
I think we were about 20.
I was still in university.
I was in Yokohama around then.
Yeah.
My friends and I left a pub in Yokohama,
and there was a fight going on outside.
And a crowd of onlookers had gathered.
Kiyohara, let's go to the after party.
I'm not sure.
Come on, let's go!
- Why not?
- Make way!
Make way, please.
Make way, please. Excuse me.
Watch out!
Calm down. Tell us what happened.
What happened? Calm down.
Don't get violent with me.
You can't get violent.
Just calm down.
‪Shut up!
Stop it. Keep your hands to yourself.
You gotta keep your hands to yourself.
How cool!
I can imagine Junichi doing that.
- Why didn't you come talk to me?
- I couldn't.
Oh right, I was on duty.
It's not just that.
I didn't want you to know that I was
going to mixers to escape boredom.
What's up with that?
Keisuke has always been like that.
But Keisuke's dad would've been so happy
if he knew that you became a detective.
After all,
you carried on his legacy.
Not at all.
I could never carry on his legacy.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
I grew up without a dad,
so I got so attached to Keisuke's pops.
Pops?
- He always called him that, huh?
- Yeah.
I called him "Dad,"
but he called him "Pops."
Even though he was my dad.
Pops.
Sorry…
He called him Pops!
What is it, Junichi?
Kendo was so much fun.
Do you remember
the team competition in sixth grade?
How could we ever forget that?
Naoto cried because he lost his match.
Yeah.
So I had no choice but to win.
At that moment,
Maki was a goddess in my eyes.
You were so cool.
I knew that if I won my match,
our team would win.
Yeah, since Keisuke and Junichi
were up next after Maki.
So there was no way we'd lose.
MITSUBA CITY KENDO CHAMPIONSHIP
- All right!
- Match!
- Hooray!
- You did it!
Come back here!
I'm so sorry.
Keisuke, come back here now.
You too, Junichi!
He got so mad at us for that.
- Junichi!
- Yeah,
because we were in the middle
of a competition.
Of course Pops would get mad.
- He's calling him Pops again.
- Pops.
Sorry.
That thing we always did after practice
was fun too, huh?
Oh, that cafe?
What was it called?
- Saboten.
- Yeah!
There was a broken arcade machine
that we played endlessly with one coin.
Yeah, I remember that.
Is that cafe still in business?
Do you know, Naoto?
I'm not sure.
- Is the owner still alive? He was old.
- He was only like 50 back then.
But he was so unfriendly.
- Yeah, he sure was.
- Let's go see if it's still there.
- What?
His finger was totally inside the cup.
‪His outfit hasn't changed at all.
He hasn't changed at all.
He's the same as 20 years ago.
He looks exactly the same.
Yeah, he's still in shape.
Whoa, look at this!
- I remember this!
- Yeah me too!
How nostalgic!
I got the lucky one.
I bet the price hasn't changed either.
- Never mind, it has.
- It changed.
That's only natural.
- The price went up.
- Understandable.
What should we order?
We've got to order our usual combo set.
- Yeah.
- Both the drink and the entree?
- Of course!
It's so much food.
Speaking of which, Naoto, you always
took the cherry pits home with you,
didn't you?
Yeah, he did.
You planted them, right?
What happened to them?
Um…
He didn't plant them.
Why?
Naoto took back the seeds and the stem,
and what he wanted was the stem.
- The stem?
- Yeah.
What are you guys laughing about?
I told Naoto that if he could tie the stem
into a knot with his tongue,
he'd become a good kisser.
You told him that?
Let's do it.
Okay, give it a try.
Seriously?
You guys are idiots.
- You practiced with the stems?
- I tried so hard to tie a knot.
- I didn't think he'd really do it.
- No way, you knew he'd do it.
Yeah.
You're horrible.
Oh.
Really?
- He did it.
- What?
Are you serious?
You tied it with your hands.
No he didn't use his hands.
He's an amazing kisser now.
- He's a really good kisser now.
- Ew!
Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
We used to come here a lot
- when we were young.
- Yes.
Kendo, right?
- What?
- You remember us?
What?
- Wait!
- No way!
Look at this!
- Wow! No way!
- This is so nostalgic.
Ready,
say cheese.
MITSUBA CITY KENDO CHAMPIONSHIP
The Naoto we grew up with
is now the next president
of the Sakuma Land Development Group.
Not that I do anything special.
Hey Naoto,
you're building a big facility on the site
of our old elementary school, right?
Yeah.
Keisuke is in charge of the design.
- I see.
- Yeah, it's a big project.
Thank you, future President.
Stop that.
It's all thanks to the future President?
You too, Maki?
Keisuke's company
won the rights, fair and square.
But why a shopping mall
and a community center all of a sudden?
The gymnasium was used
for a day care center up until now, right?
Well, the building had to be demolished
because it was old and dilapidated.
Construction will start soon.
What will happen to that?
The protesters?
No…
Our time capsule.
Let's go there right now.
What?
Let's open it…
The time capsule.
Are you serious?
- Why open it?
- The gun…
Junichi, you're okay with it
since you're a detective?
No way,
in fact it'll be even worse for you.
We hid the gun that caused such
a stir back then. If that gets out…
Let's go.
Junichi never changes.
Yeah.
Just a little further.
- Where is it?
- A little further.
- Junichi.
- What?
Let's go this way.
- This way?
- Yeah.
It's closer that way.
No, this way is closer.
Just choose which way is best.
Let's split into two groups.
Only Keisuke and I know the route.
- Which way do you want to go, Maki?
- Let's do rock, paper, scissors.
Rock, paper, scissors.
- I got paper.
- Me too.
You and me, Naoto.
All right, let's go!
What? Wait for me.
Come on.
- Hurry up, Naoto.
- Wait.
- Naoto.
- Sorry.
Come on, Naoto.
Hurry up.
‪Wow.
Let's go.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Keisuke. What's wrong?
I don't know…
But I heard
a gunshot nearby.
Wait…
- Where's Naoto?
- He's behind me.
Where's Naoto?
What?
NO TRESPASSING
- Naoto!
Naoto!
- I'll go look for him.
- Naoto!
I'll go too.
Maki, head back.
Call the police.
By myself?
I'll look for Naoto.
Keisuke, you should go with her.
What?
Take care of Makiko.
Okay.
- Naoto!
- Makiko.
Let's go, Makiko.
Come on, Makiko.
Naoto.
What's the matter? Are you okay?
Can you walk over there?
It's okay.
Take your time.
That's good.
It's okay.
Sit here.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'll go check things out.
You stay here.
No, I'll go with you.
It's all right.
Junichi and Naoto are…
Let's hurry and call the police.
We're going to run away?
We're doing this
to save Junichi and Naoto.
Then go by yourself, Keisuke.
Hurry!
- Are you okay?
- Naoto.
Are you okay?
Where's Junichi?
Junichi!
- Is everything all right?
- Junichi.
- What's wrong?
- Where's the police?
- Well…
- Call them right now.
What happened?
You shouldn't go over there.
Don't go.
Junichi.
Your pants are wet.
Dad!
I'll be leaving now! Bye!
Detective Ito!
I'm Nagai.
Have you known Detective Tobina for long?
I've known him ever since
he came here two months ago.
In other words,
Detective Tobina came here,
and shortly after,
the latest incident occurred?
Yes, I guess so.
I see.
Dad!
No!
- No!
- Dad!
When I got here,
it was too late.
There's another dead person over there.
I think it's the bank robber.
My dad
took him down?
I think so.
Keisuke.
- Keisuke.
- What are you doing?
Keisuke!
Will this really be all right?
The detective is telling us to dig it up.
But even if it's Junichi
telling us to do so,
why do we need to dig it up
after all this time?
No one else is around, right?
What I'm about to tell you
is confidential information.
I'm telling you this because
we are involved in this case,
but I need you to keep this a secret.
- What is it all of a sudden?
- You have to keep this between us.
Promise me.
Okay.
I promise.
I promise too.
Naoto's older brother,
Hideyuki Sakuma, was found dead…
in the office
above Smile Sakuma.
The estimated time of death
is 10:00 p.m. on Saturday night.
The owner of the hardware store next door
heard what sounded like a gunshot.
The bullet extracted from the body
was fired
from Kazuo Kiyohara's…
From Pops'…
The bullet was fired from
the gun that belonged to Keisuke's father.
It was identified as his gun.
That can't be.
There's no doubt about it.
The gun that was placed
in the time capsule,
and buried here,
is the murder weapon that killed Sakuma.
The only ones who knew
about the buried gun,
were the four of us.
‪At last, all the players will be present.
‪You're saying that I have an accomplice?
‪"Raise your hand, and I’ll arrest you."
‪-That's what you're saying!
‪-That's not what i'm saying!
‪I didn't open the time capsule.
‪Okay.
‪I believe you.
‪THIS DRAMA IS A FICTION
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita